Beacon College Celebraci de la Mujer Latina Oral History Project OHP002
People's Archive, MLK Library
Beacon College Celebración de la Mujer Latina Oral History Project
1980
People's Archive, MLK Library
Beacon College (Leesburg, Fla.)
OHP002
2.5 Linear feet
3 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Transcripts Materials in this series include transcripts and indexes for most interviews. Series 2: Interviews Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies of each audio cassette except for 02-04, 02-08, 02-20, 02-21, 02-22, 02-23, and 02-24.
Biographical / Historical
Beacon College was an independent higher educational institution licensed to award AA, BA and MA degrees. The college was founded in 1971 as a Campus-Free College in Boston, MA, but maintained an office in Washington DC on Ontario Road, NW. The "College has no buildings, teaching faculty, or course schedule which all learners must use. Instead, Beacon College students work with College appointed Program Advisors, in thier own communities, to develop their own degree curriculum plan and to achieve their own learning goals"
Custodial History
Beacon College conducted these interviews in 1980 and the tapes and transcripts were transferred to the Library without a deed of gift in the early 1980s. Following digitization, an effort was made to reach out to the project director to obtain additional information about the project and to have the collection formally transferred to the Library. A Deed of Gift was formally signed in 2018.
Scope and Contents
In 1981, Beacon College conducted a total of 17 oral history interviews with Latinas who had immigrated to Washington, D.C and settled in the Adams Morgan neighborhood. Topics include childhood experiences in interviewees' country of origin, immigration to Washington D.C., family structure, work and social experiences, comparison between their country and the United States, religion, and the Hispanic community in Washington. As stated in thier grant application, the project focused on the role these women played in the community and with the organization they represented. The project's director was Barbara Zulli D'Emilio and the project was funded by a grant from the Humanities Council. The grant indicates that the project produced a slide show based on the interviews, but no slide show was donated to the Library. Indexes for the interviews are in both English and Spanish; transcripts and tapes are in Spanish.
Oral History; Immigrants; Hispanic Americans; Women; Adams Morgan (Washington, D.C.); Neighborhoods; Latinxs
- Series 1: Transcripts
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include transcripts and indexes for most interviews.
  - Juana Campos, 1981 August 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Marcela Davila, 1981 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Raquel Gomez Hart, 1981 August 20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Maria Teresa Juarez, 1981 July 16 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Isabel Marin and Delfina Alvarez, 1981 August 19 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ana Martinez, 1981 August 6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cristina Miranda, 1981 July 3 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dory S. Ortiz, 1981 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Marisa Prez, 1981 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alicia Roque, 1981 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lucita Siguenza, 1981 August 12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Corina Smith, 1981 June 23 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Beatriz Mendizebal, 1981 July 22 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ofelia Videla, 1981 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Dominga Arias, 1981 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Casilda Luna, 1981 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series 2: Interviews
  Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies of each audio cassette except for 02-04, 02-08, 02-20, 02-21, 02-22, 02-23, and 02-24.
  - Juana Campos, 1981 August 1 (Box 2, Folder 02-01)
  - Juana Campos, 1981 August 1 (Box 2, Folder 02-02)
  - Marcela Davila, 1981 September 9 (Box 2, Folder 02-03)
  - Raquel Gomez Hart, 1981 August 20 (Box 2, Folder 02-04)
  - Raquel Gomez Hart, 1981 August 20 (Box 2, Folder 02-05)
  - Maria Teresa Juarez, 1981 July 16 (Box 2, Folder 02-06)
  - Isabel Marin and Delfina Alvarez, 1981 August 19 (Box 2, Folder 02-07)
  - Ana Martinez, 1981 August 6 (Box 2, Folder 02-08)
  - Cristina Miranda, 1981 July 3 (Box 2, Folder 02-09)
  - Cristina Miranda, 1981 July 3 (Box 2, Folder 02-10)
  - Dory S. Ortiz, 1981 July 24 (Box 2, Folder 02-11)
  - Dory S. Ortiz, 1981 July 24 (Box 2, Folder 02-12)
  - Marisa Prez, 1981 July 24 (Box 2, Folder 02-13)
  - Marisa Prez, 1981 July 24 (Box 2, Folder 02-14)
  - Alicia Roque, 1981 July 24 (Box 2, Folder 02-15)
  - Alicia Roque, 1981 July 24 (Box 2, Folder 02-16)
  - Lucita Siguenza, 1981 August 12 (Box 2, Folder 02-17)
  - Lucita Siguenza, 1981 August 12 (Box 2, Folder 02-18)
  - Corina Smith, 1981 June 23 (Box 3, Folder 02-19)
  - Beatriz Mendizebal, 1981 July 22 (Box 3, Folder 02-20)
  - Beatriz Mendizebal, 1981 July 22 (Box 3, Folder 02-21)
  - Ofelia Videla, 1981 August 26 (Box 3, Folder 02-22)
  - Dominga Arias, 1981 August 26 (Box 3, Folder 02-23)
  - Casilda Luna, 1981 August 26 (Box 3, Folder 02-24)